Chong Zhou

CONTACT Information 2078 Academic Surge University of California, Davis Davis, CA 95616, USA WWW: chongzhou96.github.io

Mobile: 530-761-3414 E-mail: cczhou@ucdavis.edu

RESEARCH Interests I am broadly interested in computer vision and machine learning. Particularly, my current research is focused on object detection, instance segmentation, and audio-visual representation learning.

EDUCATION

University of California Davis, Computer Science Dept., Davis, CA, USA

M.S. student, Computer Science

• Advisor: Prof. Yong Jae Lee

Nankai University, The College of Software, Tianjin, China

B.E., Software Engineering, 2014

• Advisor: Prof. Ming-ming Cheng

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Daniel Bolya, Chong Zhou, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. Yolact: Real-time instance segmentation. In *The IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, October 2019. (Oral presentation).
- [2] Daniel Bolya*, Chong Zhou*, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee (* equal contribution). Yolact++: Better real-time instance segmentation. Submitted to TPAMI, 2019.

AWARDS

- Graduate Research Assistantship, UC Davis, 2019
- National University Student Innovation Program Grant (\$3100), 2016
- 'Gongneng' Scholarship (15%), NKU, 2015 and 2016

EXPERIENCE

University of California Davis, Davis, CA

Graduate Student Researcher

Dec 2018 - Present

- Propose a simple, fully-convolutional model for *real-time* instance segmentation that achieves 29.8 mAP on MS COCO at 33 fps evaluated on a single Titan Xp, which is significantly faster than any previous competitive approach. [ICCV 2019]
- Boost the performance of our real-time instance segmenter to 34.1 mAP on MS COCO while keep it run at 33 fps. [Under submission]

Nankai University, Tianjin, China

Undergraduate Senior Thesis

Sept 2017 - June 2018

• Implementation and analysis of a semi-automatic image segmentation annotation system based on GrabCut and closed-form matting algorithms.

Undergraduate Student Researcher

Sept 2016 - June 2017

• Develope an intelligent system that converts hand drawings and sketches into synthesized realistic photos.

Sohu Inc., Tianjin, China

Software Engineer

Mar 2018 - May 2018

- Developed an automation testing tool using image feature matching.
- Programming: Python, C/C++, Java
 - Misc: PyTorch, Linux, LaTeX

SKILLS